<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zeromq on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</title>
    <link>http://heartysoft.com/tags/zeromq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zeromq on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 09:06:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://heartysoft.com/tags/zeromq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Oredev 2013</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/11/oredev-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 09:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/11/oredev-2013/</guid>
      <description>So, Oredev 2013 just finished. And what an awesome conference. So many great talks, and so many more awesome people. My fun started a day before the conference. Jez Humble graciously allowed me to sit in on his pre conference workshop on Continuous Delivery. As a fan of the concept, and of the book, it was a nice to finally see the man himself talk about it. And of course, he didn’t disappoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZeroMQ London–Async Server Client Platform</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/06/zeromq-async-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/06/zeromq-async-server/</guid>
      <description>Here’s the code from our latest meetup. Here’s what we (almost) built:
 An async client server platform where clients and servers can be added dynamically. Communication is done over TCP. The platform takes care of intermittent network connectivity (but not long outages). While James got it running, mine fell at the final hurdle – when trying to finish the final bits in next to no time, I managed to invert the condition of a while loop .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZeroMQLondon – And Away We Go</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/02/zeromqlondon---and-away-we-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/02/zeromqlondon---and-away-we-go/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday, we had our first hands on session of the London ZeroMQ User Group. It was nice to see such an enthusiastic bunch of people come along to find out what Zero is all about.
As our first technical session, it covered some of the basic concepts – contexts, sockets, and “sockets”. We got started with some of the theory, and then moved onto getting a basic REQ-REP pair up and running over TCP – across threads, across processes, and then (with some difficulty overcoming network issues but hey – what’s a dive into network programming without network issues, eh?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZeroMQ .NET Gotcha – Remember the VC&#43;&#43; Runtime</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/01/zeromq-vc-runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 17:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/01/zeromq-vc-runtime/</guid>
      <description>ZeroMQ has an excellent NuGet package – clrzmq. It works pretty well, except for the fact that it requires the VC++ runtime. If that’s not installed, then you get an error saying MSVCP100.dll wasn’t found. And if you happen to be running in a windows service hosted by TopShelf, you get a cryptic error message saying Access is Denied (not really Topshelf’s fault). Details seem to suggest that the libzmq.dll file could not be found – or something along those lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZeroMQLondon Launch</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2012/12/zeromq-london-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 02:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2012/12/zeromq-london-launch/</guid>
      <description>We launched the London ZeroMQ User Group (ZeroMQLondon) on Wednesday, the 5th of December, 2012. We were extremely lucky to have one of the founders of 0mq, Pieter Hintjens, in town for TechMeshConf 2012 – and to agree to do a talk to launch the group. This was our first meetup, and it got a bit hectic towards the start… Hopefully we’ll do better in future ones. We are extremely grateful to Skillsmatter for providing us with a large enough place to hold the 50+ people that came (and with Udi speaking downstairs and “hogging” a large part of the London .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>