<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</title>
    <link>http://heartysoft.com/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 11:44:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://heartysoft.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing RStudio on Arch behind Firewall</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2017/05/installing-rstudi-on-arch-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 11:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2017/05/installing-rstudi-on-arch-firewall/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Arch (more specifically Antergos) for a while now. This morning I was trying to set up RStudio, and saw that the package I likely want is rstudio-desktop-bin. I tried to yaourt -S it, and during the install, it was trying in install a dependency called gstream. The specific version it was trying to install was built from source, and that source repo had a submodule named common. Unfortunately, the submodule used the git:// protocol that our office firewall blocked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure P4Merge as Git Mergetool</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2014/03/git-p4merge-mergetool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2014/03/git-p4merge-mergetool/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using p4merge as my mergetool for a while now. Yet, every time I need to configure it, I seem to be doing google searches with lots of different “ways” to do so. This is a handy lookup for the future :)
P4merge is now natively supported by Git (as of March, 2014). The latest version available from the p4merge download site automatically adds the binary path to your environment’s PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Ignore Files and Powershell</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/07/gitignore-powershell-unicode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 20:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2013/07/gitignore-powershell-unicode/</guid>
      <description>Powershell’s cool. The syntax may be opinionated, but having a proper scripting environment in Windows is excellent. Git is cool. If you don’t use git, you’re @£$££!###. Typically, I create .gitignore files from the git bash. The way I do it is:
touch .gitignore
The main reason for doing this is because Windows Explorer (or File Explorer as it’s known these days) won’t let me create the .gitignore file – “YOU MUST TYPE A FILENAME”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>