<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ajax on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</title>
    <link>http://heartysoft.com/tags/ajax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ajax on Heartysoft Solutions Limited</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 09:44:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://heartysoft.com/tags/ajax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing a WCF Service for Ajax and Silverlight</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2010/02/exposing-wcf-ajax-silverlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 09:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2010/02/exposing-wcf-ajax-silverlight/</guid>
      <description>One of the most attractive features of WCF is that you get to write a service once and expose it to be used by multiple clients using different technologies and protocols. How a WCF service is exposed can be changed simply by changing the configuration file, without needing to recompile the code. In this article, we&#39;re going to create a WCF service and expose it to Ajax. We&#39;ll test the Ajax service by calling it from ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ajax, Asp.net Ajax, jQuery – Misconceptions and Facts</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2009/12/aspnet-ajax-misconceptions-and-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 13:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2009/12/aspnet-ajax-misconceptions-and-facts/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be some confusion among a lot of developers about Asp.net Ajax. This article will hopefully clear some doubts regarding what it is, what it isn’t and where jQuery comes in.
Ajax
Ajax stands for Asynchronous JavaScript And Xml. Ajax is used to asynchronously make a server side request from a web page. It does not need a full page refresh (a full postback in Asp.net terms) and can result in a few benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show / Hide a ModalPopupExtender using Javascript</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2009/05/how-to-show-hide-a-modalpopupextender-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 06:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2009/05/how-to-show-hide-a-modalpopupextender-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>If we have a ModalPopupExtender with the id &amp;lsquo;modPopup_ModalPopupExtender&amp;rsquo;, and need to display or hide it in javascript, we can easily do this using the $find() function.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see this in action:
ASPX:

Javascript:

The code is pretty self explanatory. Hope that helps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACT: CollapsiblePanelExtender - How to Collapse / Expand Programmatically</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/11/act-collapsiblepanelextender-how-to-collapse-expand-programmatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/11/act-collapsiblepanelextender-how-to-collapse-expand-programmatically/</guid>
      <description>The CollapsiblePanelExtender is a cool way to convert simple panels to collapsible ones. It usually has a target panel, a control which can make it collapse, another (or the same) control to make it expand etc. Clicking the said controls will trigger the collapse/open behaviour.
We may need to sometimes control this behaviour from code - both client side javascript and server side code behind. Suppose we have a CollapsiblePanelExtender with the Id &#39;cpe1&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WCF .svc Gives HTTP 404 on Host, Works Perfectly on Local</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/10/wcf-svc-gives-http-404-on-host-works-perfectly-on-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/10/wcf-svc-gives-http-404-on-host-works-perfectly-on-local/</guid>
      <description>I was recently working on a project that used WCF web services extensively. Everything was ready for deployment, I deployed to the remote host, and voila &amp;ndash; nothing works (nothing WCF related). After a LOT of frustration, I managed to make it work. I found two areas which were causing the problem:
1. The .svc extension was NOT setup right at our host. You can set this in the web.config webhandlers section for IIS 7, but not for IIS 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JQuery is now 1st Party for Asp.net - Kinda</title>
      <link>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/09/jquery-is-now-1st-party-for-aspnet-kinda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 23:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://heartysoft.com/ashic/blog/2008/09/jquery-is-now-1st-party-for-aspnet-kinda/</guid>
      <description>Wow...AMAZING&amp;hellip;Hurray&amp;hellip;I mean, like, WOW man&amp;hellip;
In a very welcome turn of events, JQuery is now &amp;ldquo;officially&amp;rdquo; going to be part of Asp.net development. MS will provide support, annotated VS versions that&amp;rsquo;ll give us intellisense, provide us with demonstrations and tutorials on how jquery can work with features like the AJAX Control Toolkit, Asp.Net AJAX, client side templates &amp;ndash; and all the time without modifying, forking or otherwise changing jquery. This is surprising, and in a very pleasant way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>